Guide to the University Art Gallery Records, 1938-2005 UA.90.8.16.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Exhibitions of the University Art Gallery, 1938-2005; I.
  - Charlee Brodsky: New Photographs, January 14 – February 15, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Book Goes Public Manuscripts and Incunabula from Western Pennsylvania and the Calligraphy of Donald Jackson, April 1 – April 30, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
  - Point of Port: Local Artists Design Art for the Parkway and New Airport, May 14 – June 11, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - It's Possible: 24 Israeli and Palestinian Artists Unite for Peace, June 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Power and the Glory: Landscapes of Industrial Pittsburgh by Aaron Gorson Sponsored by Spanierman Galleries, New York, September 26 – October 1, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The Graphic Design of Bradbury Thompson: A Retrospective, October 12 – October 29, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Two Young Painters from Leningrad: Borko Gennadii and Denis Mesentsev, October 30 – November 5, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Architecture... Energy: New Works by Arthur Lubetz Associates, November 11 – December 17, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Desk Treasures by Louis Comfort Tiffany, January 20 – February 25, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
  - Photographs by Arthur Rickerby: the UPI and LIFE Years, March 4 – April 8, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Re-Investigating Myth: Hellenic Expression, April 15 – May 14, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Fiberarts Guild of Pittsburgh, June 25 – July 20, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Photographs by Mike Verbois, July 29 – August 19, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Craft and Community: Traditional Arts in Contemporary Society, August 29 – November 2, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
  - 1990 Honors Awards and Young Architects Honor Awards, organized by the American Institute of Architecture: Pittsburgh Chapter, November 15 – December 16, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - A Personal Journey: Women Artists in conjunction with a National Conference on "The Obstacle Course Professional Women Past to Present", March 22 – April 28, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 29-31)
  - Art for AIDS: Exhibition and Auction, June 3 – 5, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Lifestyles: An Exhibition of Seventeen African American Artists, August 4 – August 17, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
  - And There Was a Train Full of Children, the Works of Gene Fellner, October 6 – October 26, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - American Institute of Architects: Pittsburgh Chapter Design Awards, 1991 Annual Exhibition, November 5 – December 1, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Original Prints, 1580 – 1850, as Gifts, from the Golden Calf Gallery, on sale to benefit the Friends of the Frick Fine Arts and Asian Art from the Collection of the University Art Gallery, December 6 – December 15, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Portraits of Fromer Principals, Chancellors, and the Presidents of the University of Pittsburgh, February 17 - March 2, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hard Choices/Just Rewards II, March 7 - April 14, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - National Student Art Exibition, June 13 - June 27, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Photo Show, July 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Silver Eye Third Biennial Auction, October 30 – November 5, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Out of the Shadows, November 8 – December 6, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Callot and the Italian Theater: Works from the University Art Gallery, December 11 – January 17, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Byzantine Art and the Byzantine Tradition in Pittsburgh, February 12 – March 7, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
  - Pop Art: The Collection of the Pennsylvania Public School Employees' Retirement System, March 19 – April 18, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Models of Buildings by Frank Lloyd Wright, April 23 -28, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Art for AIDS: Exhibition and Auction, May 7, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The Artist Looks at Industrial Pittsburgh 1836 – 1993 Factory and Landscape: Artists Look at Industry, June 3 – June 30, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
  - The International Year of Crafts, September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Art with a Heart, September 1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Hands of Praise, October 3 – October 31, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Planning the Pitt Campus: Dreams and Schemes Never Realized, November 5 – December 17, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 26-28)
  - The Way of the Seeded Earth, January 14 - February 13, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Spain and Islam: Art and Artifacts, an Exhibition in Honor of Professor John W. Williams Distinguished Service Professor of Fine Arts, February 25 – April 3, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
  - Callot: Prints from the Permanent Collection, April 19 - May 1, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - International Resuscitation Research Center Exhibition, May 6 – May 8, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Tea and Circumstance in East and West, May 13 – June 12, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Art for AIDS: Exhibition and Auction, June 30, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Drawing on Worker Culture: Labor and Political Cartoons, August 22 – October 2, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Art With a Heart, September 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Kawese Hasui and His Context: a Collection of Japanese Prints from Private Collections and Ceramics East and West: Cross currents in Art Pottery, October 22 – December 15, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Woodblock Prints of Johannes Lebek, January 19 – March 5, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Images of a Semester at Sea: Photographs by Alan Arellano, January – February 1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Prague Secret Fire, March 19 – April 23, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
  - Rare Books: a History of Medicine Exhibition featuring rare books from University of Pittsburgh Libraries, May 10 – May 22, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Kim In Duck: Watercolor Paintings of Korea, May 30 – June 9, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Art for AIDS: Exhibition and Auction, June 14, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Life and Art of Lois Mailou Jones, September 6 – October 8, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Michael Berger Print Conference: Akira Kurosaki, September 29 – September 30, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Garden Show (Barny Hannigan), September - October 1995 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Old and New Works from the Chinese Collection of the University of Pittsburgh to Honor Professor Chu-Tsing Li, Visiting Mellon Professor, October 16 – October 27, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Work by Contemporary Wuhan Artists Loaned by Bond Street Gallery to Honor Pittsburgh Wuhan Friendship Committee, Inc., October 16 – October 27, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Philip Pearlstein, Works on Paper, a Retrospective, November 4 - December 17, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - Alvaro Aalto and its Contemporary Design, January – February 1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Works from the Permanent Collection of the University Art Gallery, January 18 – February 10, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Studio Arts Faculty Show, February 15 – March 24, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Reggio Pittsburgh Project: One Hundred Languages of Children, April 11 – May 30, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Art for AIDS: Exhibition and Auction, June 20, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Samuel Parsons, Jr. and the Art of Landscape Architecture, September 12 – October 20, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Printmakers' 96, an International Juried Exhibition sponsored by the Pittsburgh Print Group, November 1 – December 15, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Nature as Muse I: Patricia Tobacco Forrester Watercolors and Nature as Muse II: Color Drawings by David Shirm, an Exhibition sponsored by Michael Berger Gallery, February 14 – March 30, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Nature as Muse II, March 1 - 30, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Studio Arts Student Exhibition, April 9 – 27, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Art for AIDS (Preview and Auction), June 2 – 6, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - The Narrative Connection: Representing Identities, October 9, 1997 – January 4, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Asian Art front cases by Museum Studies student spring 1998, February 13 - April 3, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Images of African Americans from the Civil War Era, February 13 - April 3, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Studio Arts Faculty Show, January – February 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Studio Arts Student Show, April 8 – 26, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Artfully Inscribed: Calligraphy from the UAG Permanent Collection Bound in Time: Five Centuries of Fine Bindings from the Frick Fine Arts Library Rare Books, May 11 – August 28, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Art for AIDS, June 22 - June 25, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Creating a Sense of Place: Devotion Builds a Campus In the Public Eye: A Century of Art and Architecture on the University of Pittsburgh Campus (video), September 14 – December 11, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 40 Years of Collecting: Selections from the Collection of the Westmoreland Museum of American Art, January 19 – March 27, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
  - Studio Arts Student Exhibition, April 14 - May 3, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Half-a-Century of Chinese Woodblock Prints: From the Communist Revolution to the Open-Door Policy and Beyond, 1945 – 1998, September 24 – December 4, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 13-19)
  - Recent Works by Uwe Wittwer, a contemporary Swiss artist, January 18 – March 4, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Books & Beyond: Artists' Books from Ohio Valley Collections, March 14 – April 1, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Studio Arts Student Exhibition, April 12 – April 30, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Qing Dynasty Jade, December 2000 – May 2001 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Cross Currents, October 2 – December 1, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 24-25)
  - Faculty Show, January 18 – March 1, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Annual Student Exhibition, April 11 – 25, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Representing Western Pennsylvania: Three Centuries of Landscape Painting, October 5 - December 7, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 28-30)
  - The Holocaust in the Paintings of Valentin Lustig, January 16 – March 22, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Annual Student Exhibition Studio Arts, April 10 – April 24, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - I Gave You My Song: The Art of Ora Lerman, October 4 – December 6, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - Turkish Art Exhibition, Spring 2003 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Studio Arts Architectural Studies Student Exhibition, Spring 2003 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ancient Chinese Art: Past Meets Future, Spring 2003 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Studio Arts Faculty Exhibition, January 16 – February 15, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Associated Artists of Pittsburgh, April 20 - July 22, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Flower and Bird Motif: An Asian Tradiion, Summer 2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Taking Flight: Selected Prints from John James Audubon's Birds of America, September 18 – December 5, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13-18)
  - Divinities, Demons, Kings, and Clowns: Puppetry of India and Southeast Asia, February 13 - March 27, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Associated Artists of Pittsburgh New Members Exhibition, May 21 -June 30, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Out of Time, Out of Place, Out of China: Reinventing Chinese Tradition in a New Century, October 1, 2004 – February 25, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - A Sense of Place: Contemporary African American Art, October 6 – December 9, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 4-7)
- Exhibition Catalogs, 1938-1988; II.
  This series contains catalogs for University Art Gallery exhibits for which we do not have the complete exhibit files.
  - Exhibition Painting Loaned to the Departmetn of Fine Arts by Miss Helen Clay Frick, January 17 - February 28, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Contemporary American Ceramics Selected from the Eleventh National Ceramic Exhibition, April 16 - May 7, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition of the work of Joseph R. Woodwell, November 30, 1953 - January 2, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Painters from Pittsburgh: The Frontier Settlement and the Industrial Development, Jaunary 15 - February 12, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Iranian Art and Some of Its Influences, January 23 - February 24, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - French Painting, XVII - XVIII Centuries, November 6th, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Everett Shinn: An Exhibition of His Work, February 25 - March 28, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Twelve Masterpieces of Italian Painting from the Fourteenth and Fifteenth Centuries, Executed in the Original Techniques by Nicholas Lochoff (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Medieval Frescoes From Yugoslavia, September 10 - 30, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - The Twentieth Century Print as Seen Through the Lydia and Harry L. Winston Collection, December 14, 1971 - January 16, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Virgil Cantini Enamels, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Needlework: Portrait of an Unknown Artist, November 8 - December 8, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Reid and Stuhldreher, PC A One Hundred Year Old Retrospective: The Architect's Drawing as a Communicating Medium, March 20 - April, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 20)